RÉSUMÉ

John Krug

DoB: 12/01/1963

email: jh.krug@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jhkrug

GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug GitLab: https://www.gitlab.com/libtics

Other: https://jhkrug.github.io

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I'm an experienced information technology and documentation professional. I've worked in development, systems and data management, support, and technical documentation, sometimes in leadership roles.

Most recently, after a late career pivot, I have been enjoying technical writing using a docs-as-code approach in documentation teams first at OutSystems and now at SUSE.

SKILLS

I have worked in large and small teams in a range of organizations. For the past six years this has all been remote work with geographically dispersed teams. I have been an employee, manager, and a director/owner so have a wide perspective.

I'm currently working in agile documentation development teams using Git, GitHub, Markdown, asciidoc and a variety of enterprise applications. The work is documenting cloud products and developer tools.

At Lancaster, I worked at system management, data wrangling, Oracle, SQL, ETL processes, and data visualization. I applied these skills to library management and analytics processes. I did frequent training sessions for library staff.

I am familiar with Linux, and have used Windows and MacOS. I have coded in many languages over the years (Assembly, C, OCCAM, SQL, Lua, Python, Shell, etc.). I have written much training material and documentation about systems integration, automation, and data management. I have, many times, learned new technologies, using and integrating them.

My first language is English. I'm learning Spanish and finding it difficult. But, perseverance is key. As a reminder, I have a prize for perseverance from 1980 sitting on my desk.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Technical Writer, SUSE, July 2023 - Present

I'm part of the SUSE Rancher cloud engineering division. I write documentation for open-source cloud products, working daily with engineers and project managers. My primary project is Kubewarden (CNCF sandbox). Documentation tools are GitHub, git, vsCode, Docusaurus, Markdown, AsciiDoc and Antora. It's a fully remote role using a range of collaboration tools.

My breadth and depth of experience provides mentoring and guidance to less experienced team members.

I presented at SUSECON24, in Berlin, on aspects of the SUSE approach to documentation. I presented two sessions at SUSECON25 in Orlando.

Senior Technical Writer, OutSystems, *July 2022 - May 2023*

I worked on product documentation for the OutSystems low-code product set. The products provided low-code workflow development tools for web and mobile applications. I worked as an agile team lead, updating and writing documentation. We used Zoom, JIRA, Confluence, Figma, Google Workspace, markdown, git, VScode, and GitHub. I enjoyed being back in full-time work in a highly technical, client-focused organization. This was a fully remote role.

Library Consultant, Independent, May 2017 - July 2022

For the University of Leeds, I developed Alma and Primo analytics training materials for library staff. The CC-licensed training materials website is archived at Netlify. The training materials are in asciidoc and Antora with accompanying video material. The source is on GitLab. This was a fully remote role.

In April 2018, I organized and presented at a training workshop on Alma Analytics for UK Ex Libris users in London on behalf of the British user group.

Systems and Analytics Manager, Lancaster University Library, *April 2002 - March 2017*

I had 15 years at Lancaster University Library, starting as the Library Systems Coordinator implementing a newly purchased Ex Libris library management system.

For IGeLU[1] and ELUNA[2], I established the first Analytics group[3] to promote use of Alma Analytics in HE libraries. I coordinated 14 library professionals around the world helping build the wider Ex Libris Analytics community at conferences and workshops.

I gained an ILM Level 5 qualification in leadership and management. I received a Lancaster University staff award for outstanding achievement.

Before 2002

- With colleagues, I started an IT consultancy, Xinetica Ltd (1996-2002). We did well, for a few years, before the first internet crash and internal rifts. During this time I worked at ASDA and the Financial Services Authority.
- I was a consultant at Protek (1994-1996) working at North West Water.
- I was a systems administrator at Barclays de Zoet Wedd (1992-1993) in London. I worked on the FX derivatives desk. A high pressure environment.
- During 1991, after my M.Sc. I worked at the NTSC[4] with parallel processing industrial research and the INMOS transputer.
- I was a Lance Corporal in the British Army, Royal Artillery (1983-86). I can drive a tracked armored personnel carrier if necessary:-).

EDUCATION

- 1990-1991 University of Sheffield, M.Sc. Software Systems Technology
- 1985-1989 Open University (UK), undergraduate courses at in mathematics and computing.

REFERENCES

From Masud Khokhar.	From David Summers
---------------------	--------------------

PORTFOLIO

- GitHub: https://www.github.com/jhkrug
- GitLab: https://gitlab.com/libtics
- Libtics: https://libtics.netlify.app
- A very occasional blog: https://jhkrug.github.io.

FOOTNOTES

- 1 International Group of Ex Libris Users
- 2 Ex Libris Users of North America
- 3 Analytics SIWG (Special Interest Working Group)
- 4 National Transputer Support Centre in Sheffield. UK government funded to promote parallel processing using the INMOS Transputer. The Transputer was a microprocessor with facilities enabling massive parallelism when connected with other transputers.